Matthew Farquharson

UX/UI Designer

763-607-7210 | matthewfarquharson@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Portfolio | GitHub

SUMMARY

I am a product designer with an emphasis on user research and information architecture. As a user centered designer, I think that by studying and observing cognitive and behavioral patterns, one can design an experience with the ability to influence human behavior. If you're interested in working with someone who values the importance of designing user centered products while improving the ROI of the business, please reach out. I'd love to talk with you.

PROJECTS

Kudu

View Demo

Lead UX / UI Designer

March 2020

Kudu empowers digital content creators to manage, share, and track their assets. Designed for both desktop and mobile devices, it is essentially a social media management platform with standard drive features. Users can post their content to all of their various social media accounts and use basic analytics to track their post activity.

BusyBus

View Demo

Lead UX / UI Designer

December 2019

BusyBus is a simple mobile transit that allows users to track when certain buses are arriving at specific bus stops.

EXPERIENCE

Thinkful Apprenticeship

Product Design Flex

October 2019 – Present

- Learned industry best practices and design process standards with a focus on UX research, visual design, and front-end development
- Created and deployed projects while learning new tools and frameworks by collaborating several hours every week with a lead product designer at Amazon.

Quinn Violins & Fret Central

Sales Representative

May 2018 - March 2020

As the primary sales representative, it was my responsibility to create online product listings on Amazon and Reverb, and to assist all customers. While answering questions about products with potential customers, I eventually became more and more familiar with common questions that prevented customers from simply purchasing the item. I made it my goal to design flawless product listings with all of the necessary information to enable customers to make the purchase. Shortly after doing this, the music shop noticed an increase in online sales, further validating my desire to explore a career in UX.

EDUCATION

University of Colorado, Boulder
Bachelor of Music, Violin Performance

GPA: 3.6 | 2013 - 2018

SKILLS

User surveys Personas
Wireframing User flows
Usability testing HTML/CSS
Journey mapping JavaScript
Competitive analysis